Antoine Soetewey

antoinesoetewey.com

Summary

I am a PhD candidate in statistics at UCLouvain in Belgium, within the Institute of Statistics, Biostatistics and Actuarial Sciences. My research interests focus on bio-statistical procedures applied to cancer patients. In parallel with my doctoral thesis, I am teaching assistant for several courses in statistics and probability at bachelor and master's level and I provide trainings and workshops in data science, statistics and R programming for UCLouvain's technology platform for Statistical Methodology and Computing Service. In my spare time, I write about statistics and code in R via my blog statsandr.com.

Education

	Lucation
2017 – Present	 PhD in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium - Thesis: Life and health actuarial pricing: a biostatistics approach (supervisors: Prof. Catherine Legrand and Prof. Michel Denuit) - All publications, posters and talks available at antoinesoetewey.com/research
2015 – 2016	MSc in econometrics & operations research – Maastricht University, Netherlands - Thesis: <i>Combining professional and survey forecasts for macroeconomic data</i> (supervisor: Prof. Nalan Basturk)
2013 – 2015	MSc in economics – KULeuven, Belgium - Thesis: Negativity bias and framing effect in charity donations: a field experiment (supervisor: Prof. Jo Swinnen)
Aug – Dec 2014	Faculty exchange – University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, USA
2010 - 2013	BSc in economics & management sciences – UCLouvain, Belgium
	Experience
2017 – Present	Teaching assistant in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium
	- See all courses at antoinesoetewey.com/teaching
2018 – Present	Consultant and instructor in statistics & R programming – SMCS - Statistical and data analysis consulting for professionals, academics and students
	- Instructor for UCLouvain's university certificates "Introduction to data analysis
	with R", "Junior data analyst" and "Practice of statistics with R"

2018 - Present Private tutor in statistics and consultant in data science

- Private tutor for students and academics. See easystat.be
- Data science consultant for professionals and companies. See datanalyze.be

2016 – 2017 **Data scientist** – Business & Decision, Belgium

- Involved in several projects focusing on data science and data visualization

Technical skills & languages

Software

- See all projects at antoinesoetewey.com/software

Languages

- French (native), English (fluent), Dutch (intermediate)